Urban Borderlands Records MS083
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Urban Borderlands Records
2002 -- 2011
1969 -- 2011
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Pacini-Hernandez, Deborah
MS083
7.45 Linear Feet
125 Digital Object(s)
1 Web sites
Arrangement
This collection is organized into series by semester.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of oral history tapes and transcripts, photographs, and supporting documentation for the Anthropology 183 seminar Urban Borderlands. Urban Borderlands was a joint effort between Tufts undergraduates and Latino high school students from Cambridge and documents the arrival and integration of the Latino community in contemporary US cities. Through interviews, recorded oral histories, and field research, students developed a history of the Latino community of Cambridge and Somerville, Massachusetts. Research topics were determined by the class and included subjects such as: the history and trajectory of the various Latino groups' arrival in Cambridge and Somerville, their settlement patterns and primary economic activities; the role of the church, sports, culture and the media; and the relationships and interactions of the various Latino groups with Cambridge and Somerville's existing ethnic communities. As a final project, students collectively prepared a booklet based on their research, which was published by the Gaston Institute for Latino Community Development and Public Policy.
Biographical / Historical
Deborah Pacini-Hernandez is professor of Anthropology and American Studies at Tufts University. She was born in the US, her father from the US and her mother from Colombia. From the age of three to eleven she lived with her family in Columbia. After graduating from the University of Wisconsin, she moved back to Colombia for five years. She received her masters and Ph.D. at Cornell University, and was a full professor at the University of Florida, Gainesville. She taught at Brown before arriving at Tufts.
Pacini-Hernandez's research interests include popular music studies, comparative Latino studies, and community studies with a regional focus on Spanish Caribbean Latinos in the US; Latin America and the Caribbean, specializing in the Dominican Republic, Colombia, and Cuba.
Awards Professor Pacini-Hernandez has received include a Rockefeller Foundation conference grant, an American Philosophical Society General Grant, and a National Endowment for the Humanities Fellowship for University Teachers. She has published extensively on Latino and Latin American as well as Caribbean popular music, on coca, resource development and indigenous people, and Latino communities in the US.
The Tufts anthropology course Urban Borderlands is based on a course Pacini-Hernandez taught previously at Brown University. That class was principally a reading course, but students also interviewed Dominicans and Colombians living in Providence, R.I. Once at Tufts, Pacini-Hernandez adapted the class because, at the time, there were no Latino communities close to the Tufts campus. Then "she learned about Concilio Hispano, the oldest multi-service agency in Cambridge and discovered that although there has been a Latino community in Cambridge since the 1950s, there were few, if any, written records about it." Out of her collaboration with Concilio Hispano developed Urban Borderlands -- as an example of "public anthropology"-- an approach to the discipline that encourages active citizenship and contributions to communities beyond the academic world.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Dept. of Sociology/Anthropology; Hispanic Americans -- Massachusetts; Hispanic Americans -- Interviews; Medford/Somerville history
- Spring 2002, 1969 -- 2002; MS083.001; 1.0 Linear Feet; 15 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of materials from the Spring 2002 semester.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged by material type.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Legal release forms, 2002; MS083.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Dennis Benzan interview transcription, 2002; MS083.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Rafael Benzan interview transcription, 2002; MS083.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Ernest Galvin interview transcription, 2002; MS083.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Elena Letona interview transcription, 2002; MS083.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Izzy Maldonado interview transcription, 2002; MS083.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Jaime Mercabo interview transcription, 2002; MS083.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Jose Ortiz interview transcription, 2002; MS083.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Angel Perez interview transcription, 2002; MS083.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Sylvia Saavedra interview transcription, 2002; MS083.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Nelson Salazar interview transcription, 2002; MS083.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Roberto Santiago interview transcription, 2002; MS083.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - The Evolution of the Latino Community in Cambridge, Massachusetts, final project written by Andrew Hara, Ariana Flores, Galen Maze and Radhika Thakkar, Spring, 2002; MS083.001.001.00013; Hara, Andrew; Flores, Ariana; Maze, Galen; Thakkar, Radhika (Box 1)
  - Latino Cultural Expression in Cambridge, final student project written by Brigid Brannigan, L. Sean Kennedy, and Annery Miranda, Spring, 2002; MS083.001.001.00014; Brannigan, Brigid; Kennedy, L.Sean; Miranda, Annery (Box 1)
  - Latinos in the Economy of Cambridge, final student project written by Rachel Long and Richard Nightingale, Spring, 2002; MS083.001.001.00015; Long, Rachel; Nightingale, Richard (Box 1)
  - The Movers and Shakers of Cambridge, Massachusetts, final student project written by John Keogh and Kathleen Flahive, 3 May, 2002-05-03; MS083.001.001.00016; Keogh, John; Flahive, Kathleen (Box 1)
  - Student journal index, 2002; MS083.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Brigid Brannigan student journal, 2002; MS083.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
    - Brigid Brannigan supporting documentation, 2002; MS083.001.001.00018.00001
    - Brigid Brannigan supporting documentation, 2002; MS083.001.001.00018.00002
  - Kathleen Flahive student journal, 2002; MS083.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
    - Kathleen Flahive supporting documentation, 2002; MS083.001.001.00019.00001
    - Kathleen Flahive supporting documentation, 2002; MS083.001.001.00019.00002
  - Ariana Flores student journal, 2002; MS083.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Andrew Hara student journal, 2002; MS083.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - L. Sean Kennedy student journal, 2002; MS083.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Rachel Long student journal, 2002; MS083.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
    - Rachel Long supporting documentation, 2002; MS083.001.002.00002.00001
    - Rachel Long supporting documentation, 2002; MS083.001.002.00002.00002
  - Galen Maze student journal, 2002; MS083.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
    - Galen Maze supporting data, 2002; MS083.001.002.00003.00001
    - Galen Maze supporting data, 2002; MS083.001.002.00003.00002
  - Richard Nightingale student journal, 2002; MS083.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
    - Richard Nightingale supporting documentation, 2002; MS083.001.002.00004.00001
    - Richard Nightingale supporting documentation, 2002; MS083.001.002.00004.00002
  - Radhika Thakkar student journal, 2002; MS083.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Supporting material, Cambridge rental control, Cambridge history and census, 1993 -- 2002; MS083.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Supporting material, Area Four Neighborhood Study and newsletter, 2002; MS083.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Supporting materials, Cambridge shool system reports, 2000 -- 2001; MS083.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - List of articles from "Cambridge Chronicle", 1970 -- 2000; MS083.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Photocopies of articles from "Cambridge Chronicle", 1969 -- 1989; MS083.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Photocopies of articles from "Cambridge Chronicle", 1990 -- 2000; MS083.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Photographs, 2002; MS083.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - Postcard announcing reception for the Cambridge Oral History Project, 2002; MS083.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Urban Borderlands Culture Group Archive, 2002; MS083.001.002.00014
    Materials from Dr. Deborah Hernandez-Pacini's CD compilation of individual student and group work.
  - Tape one, Israel Madonado (Izzy), 2002-02-11; MS083.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
    Interviewed by Rachel Long and Rich Nightingale.
  - Tape two, Angel Perez, 2002-03-11; MS083.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
    Interviewed by Rachel Long.
  - Tape three, Elena Letona, 2002-03-05; MS083.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
    Interviewed by Andrew Hara and Kathleen Flahive.
  - Tape four, Jose Ortiz, 2002-02-17; MS083.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
    In spanish. Interviewed by Brigid Brannigan.
  - Tape five, Nelson Salazar, 2002-03-08; MS083.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
    Interviewed by Andrew Hara, Maira Perez, and Marisela Perez.
  - Tape six, James and Julia Wallace, 2002-04-29; MS083.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
    Interviewed by Andrew Hara.
  - Tape seven, Diego Mandia and Roberto Santiago, 2002; MS083.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
    Diego Mandia interviewed by Rachel Long, Richard Nightingale, Jessica Jimenez. Roberto Santiago interviewed by Richard Nightingale.
  - Tape eight, Elizabeth Ahsanullah, 2002; MS083.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
    Interviewed by Radhika Thakkar
  - Tape nine, Madgalena Riva, 2002-04-27; MS083.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
    Interviewed by Andrew Hara and Radhika Thakkar.
  - Tape ten (a), Maria Bermudez, 2002-02-10; MS083.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
    Interviewed by Andrew Hara, Radhika Thakkar, Maira and Marisela Perez.
  - Tape ten (b), Maria Bermudez, 2002; MS083.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - Tape eleven, Filipe Vaquerano, 2002-04-24; MS083.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
    Interviewed by Kathleen Flahive.
  - Tape twelve, Hilda Rosario, 2002-04-02; MS083.001.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - Tape thirteen, Lucia de Jimenez and Rafael Brea, 2002-02-01 -- 2002-02-19; MS083.001.006.00002 (Box 6)
    Lucia de Himenez interviewed by Rachel Long and Richard Nightingale on February 1, 2002. Rafael Brea interviewd by Rachel Long on February 19, 2002.
  - Tape fourteen (a), Rafael Benzan, 2002-02-16 -- 2002-02-25; MS083.001.006.00003 (Box 6)
    Interviewed by Brigid Brannigan and L. Sean Kennedy on February 16 and February 25, 2002.
  - Tape fourteen (b), Rafael Benzan, 2002-02-16; MS083.001.006.00004 (Box 6)
  - Tape fifteen, Marie Deravil, 2002-02-04; MS083.001.007.00001 (Box 7)
  - Tape sixteen, Ramon Cruz, 2002; MS083.001.007.00002 (Box 7)
    Interviewed by Ariana Flores and Rachel Long.
  - Tape seventeen, Lina Aquirre, 2002-04-16; MS083.001.007.00003 (Box 7)
    Interviewed by Brigid Brannigan and L. Sean Kennedy. In Spanish.
  - Tape eighteen, Dennis Benzan, 2002-02-24; MS083.001.007.00004 (Box 7)
    Interviewed by Ariana Flores, Andrew Hara, Radhika Thakkar, Galen Maze, Maira and Maricela Perez.
  - Tape nineteen, Roberto Santiago, 2002; MS083.001.008.00001 (Box 8)
  - Tape twenty, Jaime Mercabo, 2002-04-01; MS083.001.008.00002 (Box 8)
    Interviewed by Galen Maze
  - Microcassette, Corrine Varon and Marcos Garcia, 2002-04-08 -- 2002-04-24; MS083.001.008.00003 (Box 8)
    Interviewed by Brigid Brannigan. In Spanish.
- Spring 2003, MS083.002; 1.5 Linear Feet; 21 Digital Object(s)
  This series consists of materials from the Spring 2003 semester.
  - Legal release forms, 2003; MS083.002.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Antoinette Basualdo Interview Transcription and Report, 2003; MS083.002.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Jennie Nettik Interview Transcription and Report, 2003; MS083.002.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Jeneen Mucci Interview Transcription and Report, 2003; MS083.002.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Cesar Garcia Interview Transcription and Report, 2003; MS083.002.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Patricia Sanchez Interview Transcription and Report, 2003; MS083.002.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Vanessa Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Supporting materials: Cambridge Youth Program, 2003; MS083.002.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Cambridge Youth Organizations: Where do Latino Youth fit it? final project by Marisa Romo, Spring, 2003; MS083.002.001.00009; Romo, Marisa (Box 1)
  - Interview Reports by Elizabeth Butler, 2003; MS083.002.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Elba "Mireya" Vasquez Interview Transcription, 2003; MS083.002.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Paul Bothwell Interview Transcription, 2003; MS083.002.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Hispanic America: Systemic Poverty and the Evangelical Church in Cambridge, MA final project by Elizabeth Butler, Spring, 2003; MS083.002.001.00013; Butler, Elizabeth (Box 1)
  - Lydia Torres Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Nefretiri Lopez Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Rosa Maria Perez Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Roberto Miranda Interview Transcription and Report, 2003; MS083.002.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Herman Greene Interview Transcription and Report, 2003; MS083.002.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Santos Merino and Maria Reyes Lainez Interview Transcription and Report, 2003; MS083.002.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Christian Latinos in Cambridge: Communities of Faith that Rise Above final project by Kerry Biggs, Spring, 2003; MS083.002.001.00020; Biggs, Kerry (Box 1)
  - Patricia Cullen Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Gema Schaff Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Cira Espinosa Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Supporting Materials: Somerville and Cambridge Health brochures, 2003; MS083.002.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - The Latino Oral History Project: Health Care for Latinos in Cambridge, MA final project by Casey Rebholz, Spring, 2003; MS083.002.001.00025; Rebholz, Casey (Box 1)
  - Jose Augusto Barriga Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Roberto Arevalo Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Joshua Winer Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Paulina Mauras Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Marcello Ozain Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - David Fitcher Interview Transcription and Report, 2003; MS083.002.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Raphael Pereira Interview Transcription and Report, 2003; MS083.002.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Self-Representation and Community Building: Latino Artistic Expression in Cambridge, MA final project by Chinar Mahadkar, Spring, 2003; MS083.002.002.00008; Mahadkar, Chinar (Box 2)
  - Alba Alvarez, Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Rosi Amador Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Raquel Ortiz Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Consuelo Isaacson Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - Elaine M. Madden Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Francisca Diaz Interview Report, 2003; MS083.002.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - Mayra Muniz Interview Transcription and Report, 2003; MS083.002.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - Latina Buisness Owners in Cambridge, MA final project by Meredith Green, Spring, 2003; MS083.002.002.00016; Green, Meredith (Box 2)
  - "Face of Latino Musicians" Transcript of an interview with Joel la rue Smith by Kate McDonnell, Spring, 2003; MS083.002.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - "Face of Latino Musicians" Transcript of an interview with Cesar Villalobos by Kate McDonnell, Spring, 2003; MS083.002.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - 'Face of Latino Musicians' Transcript of an interview with Katie Viquiera by Kate McDonnell, Spring, 2003; MS083.002.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - "Face of Latino Musicians" Transcript of an interview with Elias Barahonas by Kate McDonnell, Spring, 2003; MS083.002.002.00020 (Box 2)
  - "Face of Latino Musicians" Interview Report for an interview with Mayra Muinz by Kate McDonnell, Spring, 2003; MS083.002.002.00021 (Box 2)
  - "Face of Latino Musicians" Interview Report for an interview with Carlo Bello by Kate McDonnell, Spring, 2003; MS083.002.002.00022 (Box 2)
  - "Face of Latino Musicians" Final Report by Kate McDonnell, Spring, 2003; MS083.002.002.00023 (Box 2)
  - Marcos Garcia, Transcript of an interview by Juliette Lizeray. "Solidarity Movement", 2003; MS083.002.002.00024 (Box 2)
  - Jose Sotz, Fransisco Garcia and Adolf Sanchez. Interview Report of an interview by Juliette Lizeray. "The Central American solidarity movement and grassroots organization in Cambridge and Greater Boston.", 2003; MS083.002.002.00025 (Box 2)
  - Angel Tito Meza. Interview Report of an interview by Juliette Lizeray. "The Central American solidarity movement and grassroots organization in Cambridge and Greater Boston.", 2003; MS083.002.002.00026 (Box 2)
  - Maria Elena Letona. Interview Report of an interview by Juliette Lizeray. "The Central American solidarity movement and grassroots organization in Cambridge and Greater Boston.", 2003; MS083.002.002.00027 (Box 2)
  - Mario Davila. Interview Report of an interview by Juliette Lizeray. "The Central American solidarity movement and grassroots organization in Cambridge and Greater Boston.", 2003; MS083.002.002.00028 (Box 2)
  - Mike Prokosch. Interview Report of an interview by Juliette Lizeray. "The Central American solidarity movement and grassroots organization in Cambridge and Greater Boston.", 2003; MS083.002.002.00029 (Box 2)
  - Nelson Salazar. Interview Report of an interview by Juliette Lizeray. "The Central American solidarity movement and grassroots organization in Cambridge and Greater Boston.", 2003; MS083.002.002.00030 (Box 2)
  - Final Report by Juliette Lizeray. "The Central American solidarity movement and grassroots organization in Cambridge and Greater Boston.", 2003; MS083.002.002.00031 (Box 2)
  - Cesar Garcia, 2003-04-16; MS083.002.003.00001 (Box 3)
    Interviewed by Marisa Romo.
  - Jenni Nettik, 2003-04-01; MS083.002.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Jeneen Mucci, 2003-04-16; MS083.002.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Antionette Basualdo, 2003-03-07; MS083.002.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Patricia Sanchez, 2003-02-28; MS083.002.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Jocelyn Sierra, 2003-04-09; MS083.002.003.00006 (Box 3)
    Interviewed by Elizabeth Butler.
  - Carmen Figueroa, 2003-04; MS083.002.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Paul Bothwell, 2003-05-07; MS083.002.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Rosa Perez, 2003-03-04; MS083.002.003.00009 (Box 3)
    Interviewed by Kerry Biggs.
  - Roberto Miranda, 2003-04-16; MS083.002.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Rev. Herman Greene, 2003-02-19; MS083.002.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - Lydia Torres, 2003-04-17; MS083.002.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - Maria Reyes Lainez and Santos Merino, 2003-04-19; MS083.002.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Gema Schaff, 2003-03-04; MS083.002.003.00014 (Box 3)
    Interviewed by Casey Rebholz.
  - Patricia Cullen, 2003-03-04; MS083.002.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - Cira Espinosa, 2003-04-02; MS083.002.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - Joshua Winer, 2003-03-02; MS083.002.004.00001 (Box 4)
    Interviewed by Chinar Mahadkar.
  - Paulina Mauras, 2003-04-25; MS083.002.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Rafael Pereira, 2003-04-02; MS083.002.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Rafael Pereira, 2003-04-02; MS083.002.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - David Fichter, 2003-03-02; MS083.002.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Roberto Arevallo, 2003-04-02; MS083.002.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Marcello Ozain, 2003-04-10; MS083.002.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Jose Barriga, 2003-03-28; MS083.002.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - Miriam Diaz, 2003-04-14; MS083.002.004.00009 (Box 4)
    Interviewed by Meredith Green.
  - Alba Alvarez, 2003-04-02; MS083.002.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - Consuelo Isaacson, 2003-03-14; MS083.002.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Consuelo Isaacson, 2003-03-14; MS083.002.004.00012 (Box 4)
  - Raquel Ortiz, 2003-03-28; MS083.002.004.00013 (Box 4)
  - Raquel Ortiz, 2003-03-28; MS083.002.004.00014 (Box 4)
  - Elaine Madden, 2003-02-27; MS083.002.004.00015 (Box 4)
  - Myra Muniz, 2003-03-22; MS083.002.004.00016 (Box 4)
    Interviewed by Meredith Green and Kate Mcdonnell.
  - Katie Viqueira, 2003-09-25; MS083.002.004.00017 (Box 4)
    Interviewed by Kate Mcdonnell at the Hotung Cafe.
  - John Clifford, 2003; MS083.002.004.00018 (Box 4)
    Interviewed by Kate Mcdonnell and Chinar Manadkar at the Green Street Grill.
  - Elias Barahona, 2003-04-10; MS083.002.004.00019 (Box 4)
    Interviewed by Kate Mcdonnell.
  - Jim and Julia Wallace, 1 of 2, 2003-02-24; MS083.002.004.00020 (Box 4)
    Interviewed by Juliette Lizeray.
  - Jim and Julia Wallace, 2 of 2, 2003-02-24; MS083.002.004.00021 (Box 4)
  - Maria Ellena Letona, 2003-04-03; MS083.002.004.00022 (Box 4)
  - Marcos Garcia, 1 of 2, 2003-06-09; MS083.002.004.00023 (Box 4)
  - Marcos Garcia, 2 of 2, 2003-06-09; MS083.002.004.00024 (Box 4)
  - Angel (Tito) Meza, 2003-06-24; MS083.002.004.00025 (Box 4)
  - A: Mike Prokosch, B: Mario Davila, 2003-06-30; MS083.002.004.00026 (Box 4)
    Interviewed by Juliette Lizeray
- Fall 2003, MS083.003; 1.75 Linear Feet; 5 Digital Object(s)
  This series consists of materials from the Fall 2003 semester.
  - Legal Release Forms, 2003; MS083.003.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Nora Estella Garnica, Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Jenny Gomez, Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Esther Flores, Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Luis Serrano, Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Milagro Garcia, Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Yony Orantes, Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Ana Bran, Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Eugene Brune, Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Sol Gittleman, Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Ruben Salina-Stern Chasann, Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Maria "Maryom" Grasso, Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Amilcar Lopez, Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Amilcar Lopez, Interview Transcription, 2003; MS083.003.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Leo Zuniga, Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Leo Zuniga, Interview Transcription, 2003; MS083.003.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Supporting Materials: Latino Business Community in Somerville, 2003; MS083.003.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Reflections on project by Emily Chasan, 2003; MS083.003.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - The Latino Business Community in Somerville, Ma Final project by David Pistrang and Emily Chasan, Fall, 2003; MS083.003.001.00019; Pistrang, David; Chasan, Emily (Box 1)
  - On Common Ground: Latino Immigrant Community-Building in Somerville Final project by Nora Martin-Cooley, Fall, 2003; MS083.003.001.00020; Martin-Cooley, Nora (Box 1)
  - Ana Hilsia, Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Rosa Flores, Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Ester Ulmanzar Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Emma Ramos Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - Roberto Flores Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - Luis Martinez Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - Marcos Garcia Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Alma Mejia Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - Alma Mejia Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - Alma Mejia Interview Transcription, 2003; MS083.003.001.00030 (Box 1)
  - Ana Cecilia Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.001.00031 (Box 1)
  - Ana Cecilia Interview Transcription, 2003; MS083.003.001.00032 (Box 1)
  - Salvadorans in Somerville: Changes in Family Structure and Gender Roles among Salvadoran Immigrants Final project by Cecilia Dos Santos and Lexie McGovern, Fall, 2003; MS083.003.001.00033; Dos Santos, Cecilia; McGovern, Lexie (Box 1)
  - Edith Sanchez Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Antoinette Basualdo Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Rosa G. Medrano F. Interview Report, 2003; MS083.003.002.00003 (Box 2)